planetpublish.com 2004-06-02

# Planet Publish - Privacy Policy for the BinaryThing.com Web sites

|    
**Privacy Policy for the BinaryThing Web sites**  
**Date of last update: 30 January 2002**

This policy covers the following Web sites, which together make up the BinaryThing family of sites:

  * Planet PDF [http://www.planetpdf.com](http://www.planetpdf.com/)
  * Planet eBook [http://www.planetebook.com](http://www.planetebook.com/)
  * Planet Publish [http://www.planetpublish.com](http://www.planetpublish.com/)
  * ePublish Store [http://www.epublishstore.com](http://www.epublishstore.com/)
  * BinaryThing [http://www.binarything.com](http://www.binarything.com/)

The sites are part of the [BinaryThing.com](http://www.binarything.com/) business-to-business network of online communities.

As our user community--including visitors to any of our family of Web sites, discussion forum members, newsletter subscribers and customers--is our most valued asset, we will strictly adhere to the policy statement detailed below. Please take a few minutes to read the entire document so you understand when and why we request certain kinds of information, and what options you have for controlling your personal information.

****Our Pledge to You****

In short, we will make every effort to safeguard any information you may share with us through any of a variety of possible online exchanges and transactions. We will not obtain personally-identifying information about you when you visit our sites unless you choose to provide such information to us.

We do not sell, rent, swap or otherwise disclose any personal information -- *except* in the specific case of sales or demo downloads of commercial software products. This exception is explained in Section D below.

**A. Requesting Your Personal Information**

While most information at the sites is freely available, at times we request certain personal information from users wishing to take advantage of specific opportunities. Providing identifying information is optional in some cases, required in others (e.g. PDF Store purchases).

We request your personal information -- which may include such things as email address, name, address, telephone number, etc. \-- in exchange for certain activities, including:   

  * one-time Planet PDF, eBook and Publish forum access registration (or use Read-Only guest access) 
  * Planet PDF, Planet eBook and Planet Publish Newsletter subscriptions 
  * Store purchases 
  * Product demo downloads 
  * Adobe Acrobat Reader downloads 
  * Periodic surveys and/or contests 
  * PDF-on-the-fly postcard service 
  * Other interactive components we may add to our sites 

In PDF Store we require personal credit card information and an accurate email address in order to complete a commercial transaction. (More on purchases in Section D below.) 

**B. Use of "cookies"**

The BinaryThing sites make use of so-called "cookies," snippets of information that are transferred to the hard drives of users for various purposes. The use of cookies is an industry standard and occurs at most major websites. 

  * BinaryThing makes use of a "per-session cookie" (to monitor traffic patterns), which is deleted when the user leaves the site. This cookie in no way identifies the user; its sole purpose being to monitor traffic patterns. Users can disallow this cookie by configuring their Web browser's preferences.
  * PDF Store makes use of a "persistent cookie" when users enter their details during the process of downloading a product. The purpose of this cookie is so a user does not need to enter their details when downloading another product. Users can disallow this cookie by configuring their Web browser's preferences.
  * The discussion forum areas of each site require the use of a cookie to enable users to navigate between pages and participate in discussions. Choosing not to accept this cookie will mean the Planet PDF Forum will not function correctly.

**C. Use of collected information**

The BinaryThing family of Web sites uses the information it gathers for:   

  * developing enhancements to its family of Web sites 
  * restricting anonymous, inappropriate use of the discussion forums 
  * delivering its free newsletter to subscribers 
  * internal marketing and promotional purposes 

In addition, we routinely track site traffic by analyzing our Web server logs, but nothing in that data reveals your personal identity. We use the log information (for example, length of session, pages viewed, etc.) to help determine overall traffic patterns, to determine user interests and to continue improving the site to better serve our user community.

From time to time, we may directly contact a user about a specific question, problem, comment or idea that he or she has posted -- we are always looking for user experiences to share with the rest of the community.

**D. Sharing sales data with PDF Store vendors**

As noted previously, the BinaryThing family of sites does not sell, rent, swap or otherwise disclose any personal information to other companies or organizations with one exception: PDF Store product sales and demo downloads, with transactions conducted through RegNow.com. RegNow.com is required to adhere to this same policy as regards respecting the privacy of Planet PDF customers.

The PDF Store shares collected user information with its third-party vendor partners, but ONLY about demo downloads and sales [for registration, tech support, etc] of that specific company's products.

**E. Security**

Our sites utilize state-of-the-art security technology to ensure the security, integrity and privacy of such information. Nonetheless, we are not responsible for any breach of its security or for the actions of any third parties that may obtain any personal information.

**F. Removal from distribution lists, databases**

Subscribers to Planet PDF and the Planet PDF Newsletter may remove their personal information from our distribution lists as follows:

  * For Planet PDF: Contact us via email at [info@PlanetPDF.com](mailto:info@PlanetPDF.com)
  * For the Publish and eBooks Forums: Contact [info@planetpublish.com](mailto:info@planetpublish.com) or [info@planetebook.com](mailto:info@planetebook.com) respectively. 
  * Planet PDF Newsletter recipients can cancel their free subscriptions at any time at [http://www.planetpdf.com/mainpage.asp?Web PageID=322](http://www.planetpdf.com/mainpage.asp?WebPageID=322)
  * If you have a problem, please let us know at [info@planetpdf.com](mailto:info@planetpdf.com), [info@planetebook.com](mailto:info@planetebook.com) or [info@planetpublish.com](mailto:info@planetpublish.com). 

The only way to receive the newsletter is either by directly subscribing from the small form on the home page, or by indicating an interest while registering for downloads, participating in surveys, etc. Users who subscribe to the Planet PDF newsletters will continue to receive relevant newsletters by email at regularly timed intervals.

**G. Review and Correction**

After logging in to the Planet PDF Forum, Planet eBook eBook Forum or Planet Publish Forum areas Web site, registered forum members can at any time access their User Profiles to make changes. Registered participants also have the option to receive forum messages via email by selecting that option after logging in to the general forum area.

**H. Changes to this policy**

The BinaryThing sites reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time by notifying users (through posting an "Update" notice on this Web page and possibly others, and an announcement in the newsletter) of the existence of a new Privacy Policy or any updates. Any significant change in the use of personal information would not be retroactive to include information gathered under a previous policy.

**I. Feedback**

If you have any questions about our privacy policy, please don't hesitate to let us know at [privacy@planetpublish.com](mailto:privacy@planetpublish.com). 

---|---
